Awake and Start are two functions that
Awake および Start の二つの関数はスクリプトがロードされたときに
are called automatically when a script
自動的にコールされます。
is loaded. Awake is called first
Awake はもしスクリプト コンポーネントが
even if the script component is not enabled
有効化されてなかったとしても先にコールされます。
and is best used for setting up any references
スクリプト間の参照をセットしたり、
between scripts and initialisation.
初期化処理などに主に使用されます。
Start is called after Awake, immediately
Start は Awake の後、
before the first Update, but only if
Update の直前にコールされます。
the script component is enabled.
ただしスクリプトがロード有効化されてないと実行されません。
This means that you can use Start for
すなわち Start は
anything you need to occur when the script
スクリプトを有効化するタイミングで、何か処理をしたい場合に
component is enabled.
使用できます。
This allows you to delay any part of your
これにより初期化処理の任意の箇所の実行を
initalisation code until it's really needed.
実際に必要となるまで待たせることが出来るということです。
For example an enemy character could enter
例えば敵キャラクターがゲームに登場して
the game and use Awake to have ammo
Awake を使用して弾丸の残り数を
count assigned to him, but only
割り当てることが出来ますが、
get the ability to shoot, using Start
実際に弾丸を撃つのは Start を使用して
at a defined time when that script component
Script コンポーネントが有効化されたときにすることが出来ます。
is enabled. It should be noted
注意すべきことは
however that Start and Awake will only
Start および Awake は
ever be called once in the lifetime of
オブジェクトにアタッチされたスクリプトの
a script attached to an object.
ライフサイクルの中で一回のみコールされる、ということです。
So you cannot repeat the Start function
このため Start 関数を繰り返すために
by disabling and re-enabling a script.
スクリプトを有効にしたり無効にしても再度実行されません。
In this example we have a script that
次の例では
has Awake and Start functions.
Awake および Start 関数のあるスクリプトがあります。
We're using Debug.Log to show
Debug.Log を使用して
when those two things occur.
二つのことが起きるタイミングを表示させます。
For example without this script component
例えば このスクリプト コンポーネントが有効化されてなければ
enabled we will simply see the Awake function.
Awake 関数の実行しか表示されません。
But if I enable the script I will see that
しかしスクリプトを有効化すると
both functions have been called.
両方の関数が実行されることが確認できます。
This is useful as it allows you to initialise
オブジェクト設定の初期化処理を、
settings for an object before enabling
スクリプト コンポーネントを有効化する前に、
that script component without the need for
かつスクリプトを分割することなく
splitting the script in to several different scripts.
実行できるので便利です。 (翻訳:gamesonytablet)